A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Issue Books, Series 17 FA363
Rockefeller Archive Center
- First Gubernatorial Term, 1958-1962; 2; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  - Volume 8 - Crime, Law Enforcement, Safety and Consumer Protection, 1958-1962 (Box 26, Folder 146)
    Tab 56 Press Release, April 19, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 364, Pr. 364, commenting on approval of Senate Int. 3231, Pr. 3460, making it a crime to use phone for threats or obscene purposes, April 21, 1960.
    Tab 57 Press Release, April 30, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 3686, Pr. 3991 on mitigating hardship in revocation of drivers' licenses, April 29, 1960.
    Tab 58 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 446, 608, 611, 610, 609, 605, 481, 306, 766, 692.
    Tab 59 NAR Statement -- accepting honorary chairmanship of New York State Citizens Council on Traffic Safety, July 18, 1960.
    Tab 60 Press Release, July 25, 1960 -- Executive order and report of Board of Parole on new parole procedures, July 25, 1960.
    Tab 61 Report -- Special Report of Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, December 28, 1960 (empty).
    Tab 62 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 63 NAR Statement -- NAR Address to New York State Citizens' Council on Traffic Safety, on State's highway safety program, Albany, January 16, 1961.
    Tab 64 NAR Statement -- announcement of proposed legislation to strengthen the powers of the Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, January 23, 1961.
    Tab 65 Press Release, March 14, 1961 -- Veto Memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1919, Pr. 1925, authorizing the licensing as a bail bond agent of persons convicted of crimes, March 14, 1961.
    Tab 66 Press Release, March 29, 1961 -- Executive Order, on program for improved driving safety for State employees, March 25, 1961.
    Tab 67 Press Release, April 13, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill Int. 3757, Pr. 3912, exempting Nassau County from the state minimum police training requirements, April 11, 1961.
    Tab 68 Press Release, April 18, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1430, Pr. 1430, permitting the sale of marine supplies on Sundays, April 11, 1961.
    Tab 69 NAR Statement -- announcing intention to appoint Moreland Act Commission to revise bingo laws, May 4, 1961.
    Tab 70 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3351, Pr. 3480, preventing the revocation of a driver's license when one of the three convictions within the 18 month period results in a suspended sentence, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 71 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 905, Pr. 905, prohibiting disciplinary proceedings by the Alcohol Beverage Control Board where a court proceeding involving the same violation has been dismissed, April 18, 1961.
    Tab 72 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2834, Pr. 4267, exempting bulk milk trucks from orders excluding from certain highways vehicles over 4 tons, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 73 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1398, Pr. 1398, prohibiting a requirement that a policeman issue a specified number of traffic tickets, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 74 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 1710, Pr. 5308, increasing the charges for bingo games, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 75 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3387, Pr. 3517, relaxing the supervision of children at bowling alleys, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 76 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3163, Pr. 4083, reducing the safety requirements for roof exits on nursing and convalescent homes, April 25, 1961.
    Tab 77 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 366, Pr. 5542, permitting municipal vehicles exceeding weight and width requirements to be operated on any State highway, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 78 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 700, Pr. 2808, exempting certain farm vehicles from requirements for mud flaps or stone deflectors, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 79 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1309, Int. 2344, and Senate Bill, Int. 1169, exempting certain vehicles from length of height limitations, April 24, 1961.
  - Volume 8 - Crime, Law Enforcement, Safety and Consumer Protection, 1958-1962 (Box 26, Folder 147)
    Tab 80 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 35300. Pr. 4548, permitting the towing of two new trucks in tandem, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 81 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1724, Pr. 5106, permitting issuance of limited chauffeurs' licenses to persons whose licenses are revoked or suspended, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 82 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapters 346, 821, 962, 579, 495, 795, 797, 549, 14, 507, 61.
    Tab 83 NAR Statement -- Address to Convention of Firemen's Association of State of New York, on New York's fire safety program, August 22, 1961.
    Tab 84 Press Release, December 12, 1961 -- letter to President Kennedy, on New York State's progress in traffic safety, December 12, 1961.
    Tab 85 NAR Statement -- on Meeting of Advisory Council for the Governor's Conference on the improvement of occupational safety, December 26, 1961.
    Tab 86 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 87 NAR Statement -- NAR Address at Governor's Conference on the improvement of occupational safety, and on proposals to strengthen safety laws, New York City, January 11, 1962.
    Tab 88 Report -- Report to Governor Rockefeller by the Bingo Control Inquiry, March 1, 1962.
    Tab 89 Press Release, March 20, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 2567, Pr. 2591, exempting milk trucks from orders closing State highways to certain vehicles, March 20, 1962.
    Tab 90 NAR Statement -- NAR Address to committee of New York State Citizens Council on Traffic Safety, on New York's traffic safety program, New York City, March 23, 1962.
    Tab 91 Press Release, April 6, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 624, Pr. 3595, authorizing a 15-cent fee for each game of bingo, April 4, 1962.
    Tab 92 Press Release, April 16, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 2624, Pr. 4291, permitting the issuance of licenses to persons convicted of certain traffic violations and crimes, April 14, 1962.
    Tab 93 Press Release, April 26, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3699, Pr. 5233, authorizing the sale of alcoholic beverages in those grocery stores deriving at least 25% of receipts from sales of food, April 24, 1962.
    Tab 94 Press Release, April 28, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 4973, Pr. 5414, expanding the opportunity for the issuance of liquor licenses in the vicinity of schools and churches, April 24, 1962.
    Tab 95 Press Release, April 30, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3808, Pr. 3937, authorizing a special police district for the Hamlet of Lake Carmel, April 29, 1962.
    Tab 96 Press Release, April 30, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 457, Pr. 4495, prohibiting the issuance of a summons for certain equipment violations on vehicles during a period of 7 days from notification of such defects, April 29, 1962.
    Tab 97 Press Release, April 30, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 202, Pr. 4341, prohibiting the sale of portable kerosene heaters, April 29, 1962.
    Tab 98 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 2359, Pr. 4763, increasing from 50 to 55 feet the maximum length limitations for vehicles operating in the State, April 30, 1962.
    Tab 99 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 2562, Pr. 5750, curtailing the dissemination of smut and pornography, April 30, 1962.
    Tab 100 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 637, Pr. 4746, making a misdemeanor the transmission of gambling information, April 30, 1962.
  - Volume 8 - Crime, Law Enforcement, Safety and Consumer Protection, 1958-1962 (Box 26, Folder 148)
    Tab 101 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2924, Assembly Bill, Int. 4337, exempting certain vehicles from the present axle and gross weight limitations, April 30, 1962.
    Tab 102 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapters 542-548, 954, 986, 478, 549, 358, 437, 438, Assembly Resolution 190, Chapters 893, 756, 979, 758, 759, 324, 770, 289, 299, 328, 43.
    Tab 103 NAR Statement -- excerpts from address at annual convention of New York State Police, on major advances in law enforcement, May 22, 1962.
    Tab 104 NAR Statement -- statement and letter of Governor Rockefeller's approving 1962-1963 Budget of the Waterfront Commission, June 17, 1962.
    Tab 105 Press Release, June 17, 1962 -- excerpts from TV interview of Governor Rockefeller on "Public Office" on the drinking age laws, New York City, June 17, 1962.
    Tab 106 NAR Statement -- address to Hudson Valley Volunteer Firemen's Association, on activities of the Division of Fire Safety, North Tarrytown, June 22, 1962.
    Tab 107 NAR Statement -- NAR Address at 28th Annual Conference, New York State Sheriff's Association, on police training program and boating safety, Schroon Lake, August 7, 1962.
    Tab 108 NAR Statement -- NAR Address at graduation exercises of New York State Police, on responsibilities and objectives of State police, Albany, September 5, 1962.
    Tab 109 NAR Statement -- appointment of Special Commissioner Stichman to investigate law enforcement in Onondaga County, September 8, 1962.
    Tab 110 Press Release, September 18, 1962 -- Executive Order authorizing an allocation of $300,000 to conduct investigation by Stichman, September 18, 1962.
  - Volume 9 - Cultural Development, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 149)
    Tab 1 Background Paper -- "Cultural Resources and Activity in New York State," prepared by Wallace Harrison and Katrina Thomas, September 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Statement -- submitted to President's Committee on site for 1964 Worlds' Fair, October 23, 1959.
    Tab 4 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 5 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller on legislation to create State Council on the Arts, February 13, 1960.
    Tab 6 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 313, 524, 525.
    Tab 7 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 8 Press Release, January 29, 1961 -- letter to Governor Rockefeller from Lt. Governor Wilson and statement by Governor Rockefeller, on proposed $15 million New York State theater at Lincoln Center for Worlds' Fair, January 29, 1961.
    Tab 9 NAR Statement -- statement from New York State Council on the Arts, on State cultural program, April 23, 1961, and 1961 Report of New York State Council on the Arts.
    Tab 10 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapters 541, 967.
    Tab 11 NAR Statement -- on $15 million appropriation for Lincoln Art Center, April 26, 1961.
    Tab 12 NAR Statement -- address at dedication of Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Buffalo, on New York's cultural heritage and accomplishments of the State Council on the Arts, January 19, 1962.
    Tab 13 NAR Statement -- announcement of the initiation of a new guide service for visitors to the State Capitol, March 3, 1962.
    Tab 14 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapters 344, 230, 302, 550, 343, 596, 784, 22.
    Tab 15 Press Release, August 26, 1962 -- Summary of two years of operation of New York State Council on the Arts, August 26, 1962.
  - Volume 10 - Economic Trends and Business, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 150)
    Tab 1 Background Paper -- unedited paper, "Business, Trade and Commerce in New York State," n.d.
    Tab 2 Summary and Background on Economic Trends and Business New York State -- prepared for NAR Special New York Project (Perkins-Kieffer), May 28, 1958.
    Tab 3 Background Paper -- "Problems in the Public Utility Field," n.d.
    Tab 4 Fact Sheet -- "Business and Jobs," prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, October 16, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- NAR remarks at Mineola Fair, September 6, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts of NAR remarks on visit to Staten Island, September 13, 1958.
    Tab 7 NAR Campaign Statement -- NAR Address at Annual Meeting of New York State Association of Publishers, September 15, 1958.
    Tab 8 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from NAR remarks at meeting of Niagara County Republican Committee at Niagara Falls, September 23, 1958.
    Tab 9 NAR Campaign Statement -- NAR remarks on Statewide telecast over WCBS-TV, September 29, 1958.
    Tab 10 NAR Campaign Statement -- on numerous proposals if elected, October 19, 1958.
    Tab 11 NAR Campaign Statement -- NAR remarks at dinner of Queens Republican Committee of Two Hundred, October 20, 1958.
    Tab 12 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from "Right Now" telecast presented in association with the League of Women Voters over WCBS-TV, October 25, 1958.
    Tab 13 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 7, 1959.
    Tab 14 Press Release, March 31, 1959 -- Major components of the Rockefeller program which received Legislative approval, March 31, 1959.
    Tab 15 Press Release, April 16, 1959 -- text of Statewide telecast over WCBS-TV, April 15, 1959.
    Tab 16 NAR Statement -- on appointment of Commission on Economic Expansion, April 16, 1959.
    Tab 17 Press Release, April 25, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 3079, Pr. 4735, increasing income to licensed lenders, April 24, 1959.
  - Volume 10 - Economic Trends and Business, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 151)
    Tab 18 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapter 3.
    Tab 19 Legislation -- An Act, Creating a temporary state commission to assist in developing policies to promote the growth and expression of the State's economy, and making an appropriation for the expenses of such commissions.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- Address to Niagara County Republican Committee on appointment of Special Study of State's Power Resources and Needs, June 2, 1959.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- on the Port of New York, August 25, 1959.
    Tab 22 NAR Statement -- on Labor Day, September 3, 1959.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- Address to Syracuse Chamber of Commerce, September 9, 1959.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- Address to Associated Industries of New York, on economic growth, September 25, 1959.
    Tab 25 NAR Statement -- Address to New York Board of Trade, Inc., on the future of East-West Trade, New York City, October 8, 1959.
    Tab 26 NAR Statement -- Address at Economic Club of New York dinner, on economic growth, New York City, November 9, 1959.
    Tab 27 Summary of Special Studies on Economic Expansion, Air Port Development, Public Works Stockpile and Power Resources -- Legislative Research Reports, November 11, 1959.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- Address to National Foreign Trade Council, on "New Era in World Trade," New York City, November 18, 1959.
    Tab 29 Report -- Interim Report of the Temporary State Commission on Economic Expansion, November 30, 1959 (Released December 23, 1959).
    Tab 30 Report -- Special Committee on Power Resources, December 15, 1959 (Released January 5, 1960).
  - Volume 11 - Economic Trends and Business, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 152)
    Tab 31 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 32 NAR Statement -- on Manhattan World Trade Center, February 18, 1960.
    Tab 33 NAR Statement -- Appointment of Advisory Council for Advancement of Industrial Research and Development, February 25, 1960.
    Tab 34 NAR Statement -- on New York Congressional support of measures to improve State's economy, March 5, 1960.
    Tab 35 NAR Statement -- on initial meeting of Advisory Council on Advancement of Industrial Research and Development, March 14, 1960.
    Tab 36 NAR Statement -- Address at initial meeting of Advisory Council on Advancement of Industrial Research and Development, March 14, 1960.
    Tab 37 NAR Statement -- transcript of statewide telecast by Governor Rockefeller and Senate Majority Leader, on job opportunities, March 16, 1960.
    Tab 38 NAR Statement -- Announcement on Oswego harbor development, March 29, 1960.
    Tab 39 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 237, 1064, 784, 966, 203, 690, 691, 689, 216, A. Int. 1241, Pr. 3745, Chapters 429, 428, 872.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- Address to Geneva Chamber of Commerce, on State's economic growth, May 5, 1960.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- on importance of America's future economic growth rate, June 25, 1960.
    Tab 42 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Statement submitted to Republican National Platform Committee, on Economic Growth, July 9, 1960.
    Tab 43 NAR Statement -- Address at Conference on Taxation of the National Tax Association on "Our Tax-Related Economic Problem," September 6, 1960.
    Tab 44 NAR Statement -- Address at Stanford Business Conference on "Foreign Competition and the American Economic Future," Stanford University, September 14, 1960.
    Tab 45 NAR Statement -- Announcement that Governor Rockefeller has invited over 80 nations to participate in 1961 U.S. World Trade Fair, October 24, 1960.
    Tab 46 NAR Statement -- excerpts from address to Allegheny County Republican Committee, on "Improved Business Climate," October 14, 1960.
    Tab 47 NAR Statement -- Address at New York State Chapter of Associated General Contractors of America, on "Highway Construction and Economic Growth," December 7, 1960.
    Tab 48 NAR Statement -- Announcement that New York State Department of Commerce will open branch offices in Chicago and Los Angeles, December 13, 1960.
    Tab 49 Report -- Temporary State Commission on Economic Expansion, December 21, 1960.
    Tab 50 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 51 NAR Statement -- Announcement of bids on three public works projects in labor surplus areas, January 18, 1961.
    Tab 52 Press Release, January 19, 1961 -- Address by Commissioner McHugh at dedication of Harmon-Kardon Plant, on State's economic growth program, Plainview, L.I., January 19, 1961.
    Tab 53 Press Release, January 26, 1961 -- Telegram to President, Remington Rand, expressing gratification for continuing production in Elmira, January 26, 1961.
    Tab 54 Press Release, January 29, 1961 -- letter to Governor Rockefeller from Lt. Governor and statement, on proposed $15 million New York State theater at Lincoln Center for World's Fair, January 29, 1961.
    Tab 55 NAR Statement -- Announcement of proposal to repeal 15% tax on cigars and tobacco products, to assist State businesses, January 30, 1961.
  - Volume 11 - Economic Trends and Business, 1958-1962 (Box 27, Folder 153)
    Tab 56 NAR Statement -- Address to Niagara Falls Chamber of Commerce, on State's program to assist Niagara area economy, February 10, 1961.
    Tab 57 NAR Statement -- Address at ceremonies on first delivery of power from Lewiston Power Plant (Largest Capacity Hydro-Electric Power Plant in US), Niagara Falls, February 10, 1961.
    Tab 58 NAR Statement -- transcript of Statewide telecast by Governor Rockefeller and Commissioner McHugh on "More Jobs for New Yorkers" and "1960 as Best Year for State's Economy," Albany, February 15, 1961.
    Tab 59 NAR Statement -- Announcement of accelerated construction of West Seneca School for the mentally retarded, as part of Public Works Stockpile Program, February 17, 1961.
    Tab 60 NAR Statement -- statement by NAR Press Secretary, on President Kennedy's request to speed public works as an anti-recession measure, February 17, 1961.
    Tab 61 NAR Statement -- Announcement of proposed $30 million aluminum mill in Oswego, February 21, 1961.
    Tab 62 Press Release, March 2, 1961 -- telegrams to Congressional Delegates, urging action to retain installations at Griffis Air Force Base, Rome, March 1, 1961.
    Tab 63 NAR Statement -- Letter to President Kennedy, outlining steps taken by the State to stimulate economy and requesting Federal action for highway construction, March 5, 1961.
    Tab 64 NAR Statement -- Telegram to President Kennedy, urging retention of installations at Griffis Air Force Base, Rome, March 8, 1961.
    Tab 65 NAR Statement -- Letter for presentation at House Ways and Means Committee Hearing on the Federal Interstate Highway System, urging restoration of interstate highway program, March 15, 1961.
    Tab 66 Press Release, March 16, 1961 -- exchange of correspondence, concerning establishment of new cement plant in Ravena (near Albany), March 16, 1961.
    Tab 67 NAR Statement -- concerning recent announcements of new plants and expansions in New York, March 19, 1961.
    Tab 68 NAR Statement -- Announcement of $100 million appropriation for Federal-State highway construction, to stimulate economy, March 24, 1961.
    Tab 69 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto Memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3698, Pr. 4419, authorizing public contracts to be let on a preferential basis to bidders located in labor surplus areas, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 70 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto Memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2583, Pr. 4408, reducing gross receipts taxes on meat and poultry industries, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 71 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Senate Bill Int. 22, Chapter 443, Assembly Bill Int. 352, Assembly Resolution 163, Chapters 855, 160, 744, 372, 341-345, 146, 934, 347, 348, 245, 312, 899, 908, 909, 913, 897.
    Tab 72 NAR Statement -- Announcement that Stanray Corp. of Chicago will manufacture aluminum highway bridge sections in Frankfort, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 73 NAR Statement -- Address at dedication of IBM Research Center, on IBM contribution to New York, Yorktown, April 25, 1961.
    Tab 74 NAR Statement -- remarks at symposia sponsored by Advisory Council for the Advancement of Industrial Research and Development, Sterling Forest, May 1, 1961.
    Tab 75 NAR Statement -- excerpt from interview between Governor Rockefeller and Gannett News Service Correspondents, on State's business climate, Albany, June 1, 1961.
    Tab 76 NAR Statement -- excerpts from meeting of Governor Rockefeller and community leaders of Queens, Nassau and Bronx, on State's program to attract and retain business and obtain Federal contracts, Long Island, August 1, 1961.
    Tab 77 NAR Statement -- Letter from Governor Rockefeller to Cherry-Burrell Corp. of Little Falls, requesting reconsideration of transfer of operations, September 15, 1961.
    Tab 78 NAR Statement -- Address of New York State Council of Carpenters, on the Job Development Authority, new plants and business economy, September 27, 1961.
    Tab 79 NAR Statement -- Address at National Business League banquet, on State's program to assist business growth, New York City, September 29, 1961.
    Tab 80 NAR Statement -- on the impact of the Job Development Authority on the State's economy, October 1, 1961.
    Tab 81 NAR Statement -- Address to New York State Council of Retail Merchants Inc., on State's improved business climate, Kiamesha Lake, October 6, 1961.
    Tab 82 NAR Statement -- Address at Chamber of Commerce of New York City, on State's improved business climate, New York City, October 4, 1961.